Obon season's closing in.
もうすぐお盆だから
We'll have to get a leisure cruiser ready.
また納涼船を出さないと
I hope Yaichirou's making the arrangements.
矢一郎はちゃんと準備をしているのかしらね
Did you hear anything about it?
お前は何か聞いているの？
No. He doesn't tell me anything.
いや 兄さんは何も言わない
I hope everything's going okay.
うまくいってるのかしらね
The Manpukumaru's gone too.
万福丸も もう無いんだし
He should just ask for your help
.instead of trying to take everything on himself.
あの子も一人でやらずにお前に相談すればいいのに
I guess he just hates asking
.for help from his brothers.
兄さんは弟に頼るのが嫌いなんだな
You should try to get
.along with him better.
お前も もう少しあの子と仲良くしておやり
I love him, you know.
俺は兄さんを愛しているよ
He's a great guy.
兄さんは良い奴だ
Must you be so sarcastic all the time?
またそんな嫌味を言う この子は
へへ
The night of the Gozan Fire Festival
is the highlight of summer.
夏の風物詩たる五山の送り火の宵
Just as the humans celebrate on the ground,
浮かれる人間共に調子を合わせて
we tanuki throw a wild party in the sky.
我ら狸もまた夏の夜空でどんちゃん騒ぎをする
This irresistible habit has,
without a doubt,
この止むに止まれぬ性癖は遠く桓武天皇の御代から
been passed down from generation to generation
.since the reign of Emperor Kammu.
Manpukumaru
脈々と受け継がれてきたものに違いなく
My late father used to
call this our "idiot blood."
今は亡き父はそれを
阿呆の血と呼んだ
omoshiroku nai yo no naka
You just have to make
面白くない世の中
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
omoshiroku sureba ii sa
this dull world more interesting
面白くすればいいさ
omoshiroku sureba ii sa
this dull world more interesting
tsumaranee no ga kuchiguse nano wa
Some people love to claim that something is boring
“つまらねえ”のが口癖なのは
tsumaranee no ga kuchiguse nano wa
Some people love to claim that something is boring
sore koso honto ni tsumaranai
That habit is the most boring thing of all
それこそホントにつまらない
sore koso honto ni tsumaranai
That habit is the most boring thing of all
monku wo iu no wa kantan dakedo
It's easy to complain about stuff
文句を言うのは簡単だけど
monku wo iu no wa kantan dakedo
It's easy to complain about stuff
dareka wa nannmo kurenai
but it doesn't do any good at all
誰かは何もくれない
dareka wa nannmo kurenai
but it doesn't do any good at all
hashiranai kedo tomari wa shinai
That sort of useless waste of time
走らないけど止まりはしない
dare ni mo nagareru ahou no chi
runs in our idiot blood
誰にも流れる阿呆の血
sawageba sawagu hodo kakitateru
Just party on and on, and the more you do
騒げば騒ぐ程かき立てる
nanto subarashiki hibi
the more awesome will be your days
なんと素晴らしき日々
omoshiroku nai yo no naka
You just have to make
面白くない世の中
omoshiroku sureba ii no sa
this dull world more interesting
面白くすればいいのさ
jibun de mitsukerya
The things you find for yourself in this world
自分で見つけりゃ
hodohodo ni paradaisu da
quickly turn it into a little paradise
ほどほどにパラダイスだ
ki ga tsukeba itsu datte
Before you know it,
気がつけば何時だって
ki ga tsukeba itsu datte
Before you know it,
uchouten jinsei da
you live a life of pure ecstasy
有頂天人生だ
uchouten jinsei da
you live a life of pure ecstasy
Episode Three
Yakushibou's Inner Parlor
Could you please help?
この通りだ 何とかならんか
I need you to arrange a leisure cruiser.
納涼船を手配してくれ
はあ
I thought you'd decided to borrow one
.from an acquaintance in Nara.
奈良の知り合いから借りてくることに決めたのでは？
It crashed on the way here.
あれは輸送する途上で墜落した
This time, it was Yaichirou's fault.
今回のことは矢一郎が悪かった
You're our last hope.
もうあなただけが頼りなのよ
If you're willing to beg for it,
I'll see what I can do.
土下座したら何とかしてやる
ぐ
ん
あ
ぐ
くう
ん
あ
Cut this out already!
いい加減にしないか
Your brother is in trouble!
兄さんが困っているのに
Why would you kick him
when he's down like that?
土下座させる弟がありますか
The
Six
Paths
And that's how I ended up having
.to wipe my dear brother's hairy ass.
という訳で 兄貴の毛深い尻を
拭う羽目になったということだ
You seem pretty relaxed
.about the whole thing.
の割にはのんびりしているな
I've got an idea.
あてはある
By the way, I heard what happened.
そういや聞いたぜ
The other day, when the
.God of Thunder showed up,
この間の雷神様ご着到の際
Kaisei saved our mother, right?
海星が母上を助けてくれたんだって？
Yeah.
ああ
How are things going with her?
海星とはうまくいってるのか
Who cares?
知らん
Don't try to hide it.
隠さなくてもいいじゃないか
You can tell this reliable
...brother of yours anything...
この頼りがいのある兄貴に何でも打ち明けてみなさい
even though I'm just a frog.
蛙だけどさ
Our engagement was just something
.Father decided on his own.
許嫁というのは
父上が勝手に決めたことだ　はむ
But don't you two still see each other
from time to time?
今もまだ会ってるそうじゃないか
ふむ
Yeah. I have no idea what
.she thinks about it all.
あいつがどんなことを考えてるか
俺にはサッパリ分からない
I've never even seen her face-to-face.
まともに顔を合わせたこともない
Aren't we innocent?
初々しいな
It's enough to make this green frog turn red.
緑の蛙が赤くなっちゃうぜ
Well, you can come up with
.all the perverted fantasies you like,
兄さんは勝手にエロい妄想で
むっつり膨らんでおくがいい
but I'm sorry to say it's not the
.sweet romance you're imagining.
だけどそんなふんわり甘いお話ではないのだ
For one thing, if I ended up
with in-laws like Uncle Ebisugawa
大体 夷川の叔父が義理の親父になって
and the dynamic dumbass duo,
Kikaku and Ginkaku,
金閣と銀閣のダブルクソたわけが兄になるとしたら
my life would go straight to hell.
これは生き地獄だ
Yeah.
ふむ
If that happened to me, I'd just
.hide in a well and never come out.
俺なら井戸に籠もって然るべき境遇だ
You'd hide in a well either way.
兄さんはいずれにしても井戸に籠もるの？
It might be tough on you,
but this was Father's decision.
お前は大変だが
しかしこれも父上が決めたことだからな
So what? Why should I care?
そう言われても困るよ
I'm sure Father had his reasons.
父上には何か深い考えがあったのだろうと思うよ
Or maybe he just wanted to get
.some fake Denki Bran on the sly.
いや 案外 偽電気ブランを横流ししてもらえると
思っただけかもしれない
That's ridiculous.
そんな阿呆な
He might've loved his booze,
but he wouldn't do something like that.
いくら父上が酒好きでもそれは無いだろう
Either way, Ebisugawa already
.broke off the engagement.
いずれにせよ夷川はもう
約束を取り消した
ああ
Get out!
出て行け
Don't ever show your face here again!
二度と来るな
ん
Drop dead! Drop dead!
くたばれ くたばれ
ふん
Drop dead! Drop dead!
くたばれ くたばれ
く
Drop dead!
くたばれ
I'd never seen Mother so furious.
あの時の母上の怒り方は
尋常ではなかったな
She really liked Kaisei.
母上は海星がお気に入りだったからな
I wonder how long this feud will last.
いつまでこんな争いが続くかな
If Father were still alive, he'd have
.knocked Uncle down a peg or two.
父上がいれば叔父上なんかにでかい顔はさせないよ
That's true. Father could probably
.have handled this a bit better.
確かに父上ならもう少しうまくやるだろうな
Well, just take it easy, okay?
まあ
のんきにやるとよいぜ
Father would just laugh it off and move on.
父上なら笑って水に流すだろう
あむ あむ
Port
Wine
Look, big bro!
Port
Wine
兄ちゃん 僕は携帯電話の充電ができるんだよ
Port
Wine
I can charge cell phones now!
Charging
Who would you even call with that thing?
お前は一体どこへ電話をかけるんだい？
Mother, of course.
母上だよ
But aren't you always with her anyway?
しかしお前
いつも母上と一緒じゃないか
No way!
そんなことはないよ
What about when I go to the factory?
工場に行っている時とか
ふうん
Kyoto
Gozan
Fire Festival
Will Master Akadama let us borrow his ship?
赤玉先生
船貸してくれるかな？
Well, he does hate to depend on vehicles.
先生は乗り物に頼ることを嫌っているからな
But since he hurt his back,
he can hardly move around.
でも 腰を痛めてあんまり動けないんだから
Why doesn't he use it himself?
使えばいいのに
Maybe he doesn't want
to make it too obvious
天狗たるアイデンティティの危機に
that he's dealing with
.a tengu identity crisis.
自分が直面していると宣伝したくないのだな
Not to mention that.
ま あとはそれだ
The inner parlor needs to
.be fueled by booze to fly.
奥座敷も酒を燃料にして飛ぶ
先生は乗り物にワインを飲ませるぐらいならば
Why would he pour
his wine into a vehicle
when he can drink it himself
and soar the skies freely in his dreams?
いっそおのが腹中に納め
妄想の天空を自在に翔けることを選んだのだ
ふうん
So you're Shimogamo Yasaburou?
下鴨の矢三郎か
You've grown into a splendid young man.
立派になったのう
Such nonsense.
阿呆か
What use is splendor to a tanuki?
狸が立派になってどうする
You're far too nice to them.
お前は狸に甘過ぎる
That's why those damn
.furballs cling to you like lice.
そんなことだから毛玉風情がつけあがる
I heard you passed on the position of Mt. Iwaya's tengu to another.
岩屋山天狗の地位を
二代目に譲られたとか
Yeah.
ああ 今 大阪で趣味の中古カメラ屋をやっている
I'm now running a used camera shop
.in Osaka. It's like a hobby.
How could a tengu get so
obsessed with cameras?
天狗の癖に写真機などに夢中になって
Yakushibou said he doesn't want
.any of these, so help yourselves.
薬師坊はいらんと言うから
お前らが食えばいいよ
あ
Don't mind if we do.
遠慮なく
And you even came here
.from Osaka by train.
それにしても大阪からここまで電車で来るとは
Some tengu you are.
天狗の風上にも置けん奴だ
Hey, you try flying around
.in the middle of summer.
こんな真夏に飛んでみろ
You'll cook your brains in an instant.
脳みそがうだってしまう
The Keihan trains are nice and cool.
京阪電車は涼しい
んん 情けないことだ
Pathetic.
You really surprised me, you know.
しかしまあ驚いた
When I got to Demachi, I thought
.I'd fly to Nyoigatake to see you,
出町まで来てお前の顔を見ようと思って
如意ヶ嶽へ飛んでみたら
but I only found Kurama tengu there.
居座っているのは鞍馬天狗ばかりだ
You're the last tengu I'd expect to move
.to the Demachi shopping district.
それで肝心のお前は出町商店街へ
移ったと言うんだから驚いた
I just got fed up with it all, so I let
.those folks take care of Nyoigatake.
ん 面倒だから如意ヶ嶽一円はあいつらに預けてある
Is it really okay for Yakushibou of Nyoigatake
to do something like that?
いやしくも如意ヶ嶽薬師坊ともあろうものが
そんなことをしてはいかんと思うよ
ふん
I just can't bring myself
.to like those Kurama folk.
わしは鞍馬の連中というのはどうも好かん
They're as pale as bean sprouts.
It gives me the chills.
もやしみたいに生っ白くて気味悪いよ
If you want to get rid of them,
I'll have my successor help you out.
あいつらを追っ払うなら
うちの二代目にも手伝わせるよ？
I'll pass.
いらぬお世話だ
The Fire Festival's right around the corner.
もうすぐ送り火だろ？
あ
ん
It must be so sad not being able to
.perch atop your own mountain.
自分の山におれないのは寂しくないかね？
For the festival? It's much more fun
.watching the fires from the town below.
ん 送り火を眺めるなら下界の方が楽しかろう
You can't see anything from
.the mountain itself, you know.
山の上にいては何のこっちゃ分からんからな
There you are with your excuses.
またそんな理屈を言う
Master, about the Fire Festival...
先生
その送り火のことですが
You're aware that my family traditionally goes
out on a leisure cruiser every year, right?
うちは毎年 納涼船を出すのはご存知でしょう？
I am.
知っておる
You tanuki really are hopeless fools.
全く狸というのは救いがたい阿呆だな
ずず
Would you let us borrow your inner parlor?
先生がお持ちの奥座敷を
お貸しいただけないでしょうか
あ？　奥座敷とは何ぞ？
My inner parlor? What's that?
You know, Master.
ほら先生
That little tea-room-like thing.
あの小さい茶室みたいな
It flies.
空を飛ぶ奴ですよ
Ah, that?
ああ あれか
Now that you mention it,
where did I put that?
あ そういえばあれはどこへやったかな
Oh, right!
おおそうじゃ
I gave it to Benten!
あれは弁天にやってしまった
ええ
あえ あ んん
Gimme a break!
いい加減にしろ
Why do you give everything to her?
なんでそう何でもかんでもやってしまうんです
First you give her your Fuujin Raijin fan,
and now your parlor too?!
風神雷神の扇もやってしまった上に 奥座敷まで？
You can't fly! You can't even
cause the slightest breeze!
空も飛べず辻風も起こせず
What kind of tengu—
-ただでさえ天狗としての…
-まあまあ
あ
Do you still not get it, you moron?!
まだ分からんか愚か者め
I just want to make her smile!
喜ぶ顔が見たいからだ
ああ
ん
Nishizaki Gen'emon
Rokkakudou
Cafe Tsutaya
Oike Av.
Sakaimachi
Yanagi-banba
Tomi-no-kouji
Fuyachou
Gokoumachi
Museum
Seichin-in
Ikebou-Chouhou
Temple Hall
へ へへ
ん　ん
That was all I had.
あてが外れた
It sounds like you take care
.of Yakushibou a lot.
いつも薬師坊が世話になっておるそうだな
It's really good of you to do so.
誠に関心な心がけだ
I just got stuck with this duty
.because I was careless.
うかうかしているうちに押し付けられた体です
His other students don't
.even visit him anymore.
他の教え子は寄り付きもしない
He might complain a lot,
薬師坊は文句を言うてばかりだが
感謝しておるに相違ないよ
but I'm sure he's grateful.
口先だけの慰めはごめんでございます
That's easy to say, but it doesn't
.make me feel any better.
これはしたり
Sorry. I guess I should think
.before opening my big mouth.
我ながらいい加減なことを言った
I'd say the biggest problem is how he hurt his
.back when he fell from the Demonic Cedar.
やはり魔王杉から落ちて腰を痛めたことが大きいな
う
Is that so?
そうですか
If not for that, he could have
.remained active, even at his age.
あれが無ければ老いらくとはいえ
もう少し現役で活躍できただろうし
He wouldn't have let those
.Kuramas get so uppity either.
鞍馬の連中にも大きな顔をさせずに済んだろう
ん
By the way,
ところで
ん
I heard that this human girl, Benten,
あの弁天とかいう人間の娘
う
is on good terms with the Kurama too.
鞍馬とも結構 親しくしているってのは本当か？
That's right.
そのようで
My gut tells me she might have been involved
.in the Demonic Cedar incident too.
わしはどうも魔王杉の事件も
あの娘が関わっているのではないかと
踏んでおるのだが
な
ん
少なくともお前たちの親父さんが生きておれば
If at least your father was still around,
why, things would be very
.different around here.
少しは状況も変わったかもしれん
You think so?
そうなんですか？
The Nyoigatake incident...
如意ヶ嶽事件
Now that was certainly something.
あれは痛快であった
Transforming into a mountain
.like that was no mean feat.
山に化けるなんざ大したもんだ
The Kurama didn't even
.know what hit them.
あの時の鞍馬の顔ったらなかった
Never before or since then has a
.tanuki gotten the better of tengu.
後にも先にも
狸が天狗を化かしたなんて話は聞いたことがない
Dad sure was awesome, huh, big bro?
兄ちゃん すごいねお父さん
For a tanuki, he was a great one indeed.
いやあ 狸にしておくには惜しい狸だった
Will you take Yakushibou on your cruise?
納涼船には薬師坊を乗せてやってくれんか
I'd love to tag along.
わしも寄せてもらおう
そのように計らいます
We'll make the necessary arrangements.
Take care, then.
それではな
And make sure you don't let
.your guard down around Benten.
弁天にはくれぐれも気を許すまいぞ
You can go home now if you want.
何ならお前はもう帰ればいい
I'll come too!
僕も一緒に行く
Mother's always saying I should
.try to be more brave.
心胆を練りなさいと母上が言うから
Let's be off, then.
では 参るか
Nishizaki Gen'emon
Nishizaki
Gen'emon
けほ けほ
あ
は
ん
けほ けほ けほ
けほ んん
ふ
んん
あ
ん
Mixed Udon    Stir-fried Udon
Tempura Udon   Egg Udon   Kitsune Udon
Curry Rice    Fried Tofu Sushi    Tempura Don   Oyako Don   Tamago Don   Katsu Don                            Chilled Noodles
あ
弁天様は時計台にいるかい？
Is Benten at the clock tower?
Indeed she is.
はい お見えですよ
The water has been quite rough as of late,
先日まで沖が荒れていましたが
but it's a lovely day today.
今日は本当に良いお天気で
ん　ん
ふ　ん
ん
あ
ああ
うう
You can't do it, huh?
やっぱりダメか
Sorry, big bro.
兄ちゃんごめんよ
I'm so scared that I can't stay transformed.
怖くてもう化けてられない
It's not like she eats nothing
.but tanuki stew, you know.
弁天様もしょっちゅう狸鍋を
喰らってるわけではないよ
まあいい 安心して俺に任せておけ
Don't worry.
I'll take care of everything.
Peer   less
Aww, you're so cute.
あら 可愛い
う
You must be his little brother.
弟さんかしら
ん
うん
Thank you.
ありがとう
ん
それにしても暑苦しい格好ですこと
You two must be hot in those clothes.
Couldn't you transform
into something more breezy?
もっと清々しい姿に化けてくれないの？
What's with that shirt anyway?
そのシャツは何ですか
It's not like you to brag so tastelessly.
あなたらしくもない悪趣味な
I got it from the Ebisugawa tanuki.
これは夷川の狸たちからいただいたの
You mean Kinkaku and Ginkaku?
金閣と銀閣ですか
Yes.
そ
They brought me some
.fake Denki Bran as well.
こちらの偽電気ブランも一緒にね
で？
So? What brings you here today?
今日は何の御用？
I would like to borrow the inner parlor.
奥座敷を貸していただきたい
あははは
This is no laughing matter.
笑い事ではありません
ははは
ちょうど昨日 金閣と銀閣が訪ねてきて
You know, Kinkaku and
.Ginkaku came by yesterday,
saying you were bound to show
.up here asking that very thing.
あなたがきっと来るだろうと言っていました
They cautioned me not to get
involved in feuds between tanuki
狸同士のいざこざに
首を突っ込まないで欲しいと言って
and left this lame shirt and
.the fake Denki Bran here.
このへんちくりんなＴシャツと
偽電気ブランを置いていったの
That's a pretty pathetic attempt at bribery.
けちな賄賂ですな
Indeed.
本当に
I can take any of these
.things whenever I want.
欲しくなったらいくらでも奪ってやれるというのに
Their schemes are as foolish
.as they themselves are.
阿呆兄弟なので
企みの底が浅いのです
Do you want the inner parlor?
奥座敷は欲しい？
I don't think I've ever wanted anything more.
喉から手が出るほど欲しいです
I wonder what I should do, then.
どうしようかしら
If I were to let you borrow it,
what would be in it for me?
あなたに貸しても私には何の得も無いのだもの
ん
What are you doing today?
今日は何をしているんです？
Waiting for a whale.
鯨を待っているの
There are whales here?
そんなものがいるんですか
One shows up every now and then.
時々顔を出します
Over there.
向こうの方に
When I woke up this morning,
I felt like pulling on a whale's tail.
今朝起きたら急に鯨の尻尾が
引っ張ってみたくなったの
That's why I'm here.
それで来たんだわ
But naturally, now that I'm waiting for one,
there's not a whale in sight.
でも待ち受けている時に限ってなかなか出ないものね
万事そういうものです
That's the way of the world.
Big bro!
兄ちゃん
あ
何です？
What is that?
ご覧なさいな
Take a look.
I asked Gen'eimon to fix the fan.
扇の修理を源右衛門さんに頼んでおいたのです
あなたが那須与一ごっこをして穴を開けたのよ
You tore a hole in it when you decided
.to play Nasu-no-Yoichi.
Did you forget?
お忘れ？
過去は振り返らぬと決めたのです
It's not my style to dwell on the past.
You're such a bad tanuki.
You should reflect on your actions.
いけない狸だわ
反省なさい
んっふふ
あ
ん
うう
決めたわ
I've made up my mind.
Since you're the one asking,
I'll let you use the parlor.
あなたの頼みだから奥座敷を使わせてあげましょう
Thank you very much.
ありがとうございます
But goodness me, what if you
ruin it like you did my fan?
けれども扇みたいに台無しにされたらどうしましょう
You're such an unruly boy.
あなたは暴れん坊なんだもの
I'll take good care of it.
大事に使います
そうだわ もし奥座敷を壊したら
Oh, I know!
If you manage to wreck the parlor,
I'll have you perform for the Friday Fellows!
金曜倶楽部で芸をやってもらうことにしましょう
They had just been asking me
.to get someone in.
ちょうど余興を頼まれているの
And if your performance
.isn't entertaining enough,
もし芸がつまらなければ
we'll just make a stew out of you instead.
あなたを狸鍋にして食べればいいのだわ
I don't think I'd taste very good.
俺はおいしくないですぜ
I don't mind.
それでもいいの
I like you so much I could just eat you up.
食べちゃいたいほど好きなのだもの
うう
あ
Look at that!
ご覧なさい
あ
お
ああ
う
あっはは　はははは
はははは
あははは　ふふふ
ああ
ははは
Port
Wine
よくって？
Pay attention.
こうやって動かすの
This is how you make it fly.
あ
父があっけなく冥土へ居を移した後も
Even after our father's untimely
.departure to the next world,
our mother and we, her tanuki sons,
残された母と我々子狸兄弟は
毎年送り火の宵には納涼船を出してきた
still take a leisure cruise on the
.night of the festival each year.
The thought of celebrating our
legendary Shimogamo ancestors
下鴨一族のご先祖様のことなんぞは
never even crosses our minds.
念頭にもあがらない
Sometimes we remember our father, of course,
時には父を偲びもするが
but mostly we just set the summer sky alight
.with our wild celebrations.
大抵はただ賑やかに
夏の夜空でどんちゃん騒ぎをする
That's just how we tanuki are.
狸なのだからしょうがない
Just another reflection of our idiot blood.
これもまた阿呆の血のしからしむるところだ
繋いだ手を振りほどけば
You shake off my hand
tsunaida te wo furihodokeba
いたずらに　君微笑む
and idly smile at me
itazura ni kimi hohoemu
春は嵐　ざわざわする
Spring is ripe with the roll of thunder,
haru wa arashi zawazawa suru
もう花びら散りすぼんだ
and some cherry blossoms have already left the branches
mou hanabira chirisubonda
口癖はケセラセラ
Your favorite phrase is "Que será, será"
kuchiguse wa que sera sera
I can hear you whisper it again
mata tsubuyaku koe ga suru
また呟く声がする
彼女はいつもさよなら言わずに
She always vanishes
kanojo wa itsumo
sayonara
without saying "Goodbye,"
iwazu ni
風と消える
just like the wind
kaze to kieru
I don't know what the future will be like,
mirai no koto wa wakaranai keredo
未来のことはわからないけれど
今ここにある奇蹟は僕のものと
but I'll have faith
ima koko ni aru
that little miracles
kiseki wa
are awaiting me
boku no mono to shinjiteru
信じてる
約束なんてしたくないけれど
I don't want to be tied down by promises,
yakusoku nante shitakunai keredo
but let's hold up our hands
sono te wo kazashite
その手をかざして確かなもの
and find something,
tashika na mono
手に入れよう
something permanent
te ni ireyou
それは僕らを輝かす
that will
sore wa
show just who we are
bokura wo kagayakasu
五山の送り火だーい
It's the Gozan Fire Festival!
The Daimonji, huh?
大文字だね
We can take on a thousand foes!
一騎当千だよ
呉越同舟
Enemies in the same boat!
Next Time:
The Daimonji Leisure Cruiser Battle